<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
        <name>Vertigo: Versatile Extensions for Robust Inference using Graph Optimization</name>

        <author>
		<name>Niko Suenderhauf</name>
		<url>http://www.tu-chemnitz.de/~niko</url>
	</author>
       

        <url>http://www.tu-chemnitz.de/etit/proaut/forschung/robustSLAM.html.en</url>

        <briefdescription>
          Vertigo is a C++ extension for g2o and gtam. It provides an implementation of 
          switchable constraints and enables g2o and gtsam to solve pose graph SLAM problems 
          despite the presence of false positive loop closure constraints.
	</briefdescription>

        <description>
        Vertigo is an extension library for g2o [1] and gtsam 2.0 [5].

        It provides a C++ implementation of the switchable constraints described in
        [2,3]. This extension enables g2o or gtsam to solve pose graph SLAM problems
        in 2D and 3D despite a large number of false positive loop closure constraints.
	
        In addition, a re-implementation of the max-mixture model described in [4] for
        g2o is also contained.

        Furthermore, Vertigo contains a number of standard pose graph SLAM datasets 
        and a script to spoil them with false positive loop closure constraints.
        These datasets have been used in the evaluations [2] and [3]. They can serve
        as a set of benchmark datasets for future developments in robust pose graph SLAM.
	
        Have fun, I hope this is useful. 
        Hopefully, more stuff will be added to Vertigo in the future. 
        Any comments, thoughts and patches are welcome and largely appreciated.

        </description>

        <requirement>
	Linux/Unix, cmake, gcc
	</requirement>
        <requirement>
          g2o, gtsam >= 2.0 (either one or both of them)
        </requirement>

	<requirement>
	  Quick Install-Guide using cmake: mkdir build; cd build; cmake ..; make;
	</requirement>
	<map>pose graphs</map>

	<input>nodes and edges of a pose graph</input>


	<paper>
		<title>Switchable Constraints for Robust Pose Graph SLAM</title>
		<authorlist>Niko Suenderhauf, and Peter Protzel</authorlist>
		<publishedin>In Proc. of IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS), Vilamoura, Portugal.</publishedin>
		<year>2012</year>
		<url>http://www.tu-chemnitz.de/etit/proaut/mitarbeiter/rsrc/IROS12-switchableConstraints.pdf</url>
	</paper>
	<paper>
		<title>Robust Optimization for Simultaneous Localization and Mapping</title>
		<authorlist>Niko Suenderhauf</authorlist>
		<publishedin>PhD Thesis, Chemnitz University of Technology</publishedin>
		<year>2012</year>
		<url>http://nbn-resolving.de/urn:nbn:de:bsz:ch1-qucosa-86443</url>
	</paper>


	<license>Vertigo is licenced under GPL Version 3.</license>

	<furthermore>
	  [1] Rainer Kuemmerle, Giorgio Grisetti, Hauke Strasdat, Kurt Konolige, and
	  Wolfram Burgard: g2o: A General Framework for Graph Optimization, IEEE
	  International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2011 
	  Available online: http://openslam.org/g2o.html

	  [2] Suenderhauf, N., Protzel, P. (2012). Switchable Constraints for Robust Pose
	  Graph SLAM. Proc. of IEEE International Conference on Intelligent Robots and
	  Systems (IROS), Vilamoura, Portugal.  

	  [3] Suenderhauf, N. (2012). Robust Optimization for Simultaneous Localization and
	  Mapping. PhD Thesis, Chemnitz University of Technology. 

	  [4] Olson, E. and Agarwal, P. (2012). Inference on networks of mixtures for
	  robust robot mapping. Proc. of Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS), Sydney,
          Australia.

          [5] GTSAM2.0 https://collab.cc.gatech.edu/borg/gtsam/
	</furthermore>	 	

</project>
